GRAEME STEWART

Atlanta, GA 30305

Phone: 404.509.2500 | Email: graeme.iain.stewart@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/graeme-i-stewart | Github: github.com/gistewart | Portfolio: gistewart.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a commitment to constantly grow and learn. Deep experience of HR and Finance in a Fortune 50 environment but with a restless mind and a recognition of the importance of acquiring new skills. Seasoned problem-solver and communicator, with a cultivated analytical mindset. Customer-driven instincts across a range of projects. Reputation for hard-working ethic and team-player personality.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Libraries, Frameworks, Other: ¡Query, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB,

Express.js, Handlebars.js, React.js

PROJECTS

Name: Bamazon | Github link: https://github.com/gistewart/Bamazon Deployed link: https://murmuring-wildwood-59724.herokuapp.com

Summary: Full-stack Node.js app that allows a user to select an item and quantity to purchase from an e-commerce website. The app then checks the stock quantity in the database and informs the user if the purchase can be fulfilled or not.

Technologies used include: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize

Name: News Scraper | Github link: https://github.com/gistewart/News-Scraper

Deployed link: https://news-scraper-21026.herokuapp.com

Summary: Full-stack Node.js app that allows a user to view recent news headlines from the Reuters website; save an article headline, and view, post and delete article notes. Technologies used include: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Axios, Cheerio, Node.js, Express.js, Mongojs, Mongoose

Name: Golf Player Selector | **Github link:** https://github.com/gistewart/golf-player-selector **Deployed link:** https://golf-player-selector.herokuapp.com/

Summary: Full-stack Node.js app, built with React.js, that allows a user to select a team of golfers for a fantasy golf pool. It uses an algorithm built in MySQL to re-rank players based on data from 4 areas: injuries, age, recent form and average prize money.

Technologies used included: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Axios, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Cheerio, Bcrypt.js, JWT, React.js

(All of the above projects are individual projects)

EXPERIENCE

VP, Global Compensation UPS

2014 - 2019

Atlanta, GA

Designed, developed, implemented and administered base pay and incentive compensation programs for non-union employees

Prepared and presented analyses, materials and recommendations to senior leadership Developed and drove strategy to ensure programs attracted and retained talent

Director, Compensation UPS

2013 - 2014

Atlanta, GA

Managed the annual merit increase review and planning process Recommended design changes to compensation plans Managed the topics and materials presented to key decision-making committee

Director, International Compensation UPS

2010 - 2013

Atlanta, GA

Designed and implemented new incentive plan for 9,000 management employees Analyzed and communicated performance outcomes of the new plan Collaborated extensively with building of in-house application to manage the plan

EDUCATION

Certificate: Full Stack Flex Web Development Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

Business Intelligence Certificate | Emory University, Atlanta, GA

An 8-week part-time program focusing on data storage / models, data mining using MySQL and advanced excel, data visualization and dashboard creation, data modeling, descriptive and predictive analytics and data visualization using Tableau and Microsoft Power PI.

The following certifications were later earned independent of the class: Tableau Desktop Qualified Associate; Microsoft Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI.

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Finance University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business

Bachelor's degree - Economics University of Edinburgh